

Pallabi Ghosh Das

Front-end Developer & UI/UX Designer

I am a versatile and enthusiastic lady from India, living in Denmark for three years. Currently, I am working at Mover Systems as a Junior Frontend Developer. I have been working on the iOS and Android apps built respectively on Swift and React Native. I am closely working with the interaction design as well as the frontend team. I specialize in multiple programming languages and frameworks. I have also worked as a UI/UX designer for several startups in Denmark. My task was basically to build end-to-end aesthetical design interfaces. I mainly have worked in Figma and Sketch while wireframing and prototyping the solutions. In these professional roles, I have had multiple experiences in juggling between UX/UI and Frontend tech stacks. In my leisure time, I love running, watching movies with my family, and decorating my home.

pallabighoshdas.info

github.com/Pallabi-ghosh

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior frontend developer

Mover System

04/2022 - Present Copenhagen, Denmark

Smart logistics for you and your business. Deliver unique experiences while saving time, money and resources

- My role in Mover is to write and style the front-end components that meet the business requirements and fulfill the user stories.
- Assisting the Senior Developer with the design, development, deployment, and maintenance of different mobile apps (both in iOS and Android)
- Participating in daily standup meetings sprint planning and scrum rituals.
- Technical Exposure: Typescript, CSS, React Native, Swift, Xcode, JIRA

UI / UX Designer

Teton.ai

09/2021 - 03/2022 Computer vision based patient monitoring Copenhagen, Denmark

Achievements/Tasks

- Crafted wireframe from scratch and the prototype was being beta tested when I left the position.
- Working directly with Interaction Designer and Frontend team.
- Coding the app also in Next.js and Tailwind CSS.
- Technical Exposure: Figma, Blender, Notion, Miro, Jira, Trello, Next.js, React JS, Tailwind CSS, API Integration, Github, Postman.

Frontend Developer & UI/UX Designer Intern Konsus ApS

05/2021 - 08/2021

Copenhagen, Denmark

Start-Up to promote green energy consumption

Achievements/Tasks

- Taking lead on UI and frontend development.
- Coding the MVP app for iOS and Android devices in React Native.
- o Technical Exposure: Figma, Sketch, Jira, Trello, Xcode, Android Studio, React Native bootstrap template, API Integration, Git, Postman, Miro.

Frontend Developer & UI/UX Designer Intern JOYN / PackitUp.io

12/2020 - 04/2021 Social Media start-up to promote friendship Copenhagen, Denmark

Achievements/Tasks

- Responsible to troubleshoot the classical app issues in iOS and Android.
- Migrated the code base for the mobile app from Vue to React-Native.
- During the internship, I designed and prototyped in Figma.
- o Technical Exposure: Figma, Asana, Xcode, Android Studio, React Native, Vue.js, Firebase, Git.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS



EDUCATION

Diploma Course

Hack Your Future / Copenhagen

06/2020 - 04/2021

Courses

• I have acquired a diploma from HackYourFuture in Full-Stack Web Design and Development. Learning curriculum: HTML5 / CSS5, JavaScript, MySQL, React JS, Node and Git, API integration, Swagger, App Deployment in PaaS (Heroku)

Master of Science, Geography Honours

Vidyasagar University / India, Kolkata

07/2015 - 12/2017

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Study group management app (for HYF, Copenhagen)

- The final project consists of creating an app that facilitates the Study Group Management for the entire organisation of HYF.
- http://web-dev-rooms.herokuapp.com/login

Onboarding-Flutter project and Classic Rock, Paper, Scissors Game with

- A simple flutter 'onboarding-flutter' project. I have used Flutter for that purpose.
- A simple react 'rock-paper-scissors' project. I have used React.js for that purpose.
- https://github.com/Pallabi-ghosh/Onboarding-flutter-app

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

User Experience Mentor

TechLabs

Copenhagen, Denmark

Volunteer organisation led by students of CBS that aims to teach tech skills

• I am helping the students at TechLabs to create the prototype and build the mock-ups. I am assisting them on front end coding as well.